<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blake Cole | </title>
    <link>/authors/blake-cole/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/blake-cole/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blake Cole</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 08:18:13 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/bluesea-512.png</url>
      <title>Blake Cole</title>
      <link>/authors/blake-cole/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World &#43; Bio</title>
      <link>/post/0-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 08:18:13 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/0-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hi-everyone&#34;&gt;Hi everyone!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my silly little blog.  In case you skipped over the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blakecole.com/&#34;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; section, my name is Blake, and I am currently a doctoral candidate in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mit.whoi.edu/&#34;&gt;MIT-WHOI Joint Program&lt;/a&gt;.  My high-level research objective is to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;improve the performance, reliability, and useability of autonomous sailing vessels&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.  I am incredibly excited about this project, and will try to post incremental updates over the course of the next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the primary purpose of this blog is not to disseminate my thesis research; rather, I hope it will serve as a repository for discussions about my non-academic interests, and quasi-academic side-projects.  I will focus mostly on the projects and experiences I think other people might find useful or illuminating.  Though I will do my best to make sure the information contained herein is as accurate as possible, I might make mistakes, and am counting on you (yes, &lt;em&gt;you!&lt;/em&gt;) to bring them to my attention.  I will also try to keep these posts consise, but basically anyone who has ever emailed or texted me knows that brevity is not exactly my strong suit.  There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of words out there, and I intend to use them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;autobiographical-miscellany&#34;&gt;Autobiographical Miscellany&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013, long before I began learning how to build ocean robots, I wanted to learn how to build ocean &lt;em&gt;models&lt;/em&gt;.  As a lifelong surfer, I had relied extensively upon wave forecasts to determine where and when I should try to hop in the ocean, but I had no clue how they worked.  I found the prospect of using math to predict the movement of ocean waves and currents completely fascinating.  At some point, I watched the video &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MX5cKoOm6Pk&#34;&gt;Waves Across The Pacific&lt;/a&gt;, a short documentary describing the pioneering ocean wave research conducted by Walter Munk in the 1950s, and I was hooked!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MX5cKoOm6Pk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Soon thereafter, I began working toward a masters degree at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cee.stanford.edu/research-impact/labs-centers/bob-and-norma-street-environmental-fluid-mechanics-laboratory-efml&#34;&gt;Stanford Environental Fluid Mechanics Laboratory&lt;/a&gt;, under the tutelage of professors &lt;a href=&#34;https://cee.stanford.edu/people/stephen-monismith&#34;&gt;Stephen Monismith&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://cee.stanford.edu/people/oliver-fringer&#34;&gt;Oliver Fringer&lt;/a&gt;.  These two teachers really changed my life, and taught me a useful framework for approaching numerical integration problems, and &amp;ldquo;life problems&amp;rdquo; more broadly.  I owe them both a debt of gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reaching even further back into the increasingly distant past, long before I learned how to build ocean models, I was basically just a kid who loved the ocean.  I grew up in Redondo Beach, CA, and spent most of my teenage years at the beach surfing, swimming, and playing volleyball.  In high school, I was mostly preoccupied by competitive swimming and waterpolo, and I never really considered myself to be particularly academically inclined.  It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until my 3rd year at UCSD that I began considering the possibility of pursuing ocean science as a carreer.  Fortunately, the good folks at the Scripps Institution of Oceanography&amp;rsquo;s (SIO) &lt;a href=&#34;https://coralreefecology.ucsd.edu/about/&#34;&gt;Coral Reef Ecology Lab&lt;/a&gt; gave me a shot, and let me volunteer a few hours per week in the lab.  I fell in love with the culture, people, and mission at SIO, and ever since, have remained determined to pursue a career in ocean engineering!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I hope you enjoy the blog.  Please feel free to contact me with any feedback.&lt;/p&gt;






&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;jump.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Longtime friends Mark H. and Blake C. jumping off rocks, somewhere between San Francisco, CA and Portland, OR.&#34;&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;jump.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Longtime friends Mark H. and Blake C. jumping off rocks, somewhere between San Francisco, CA and Portland, OR.&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    Longtime friends Mark H. and Blake C. jumping off rocks, somewhere between San Francisco, CA and Portland, OR.
    
    
    
  &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
